<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <generator uri="http://brightcontent.net">Bright Content</generator>
  <id>http://dev.amp.fm/feed.xml</id>
  <title type="text">Amp.fm Blog</title>
  <updated>2006-12-09T19:31:53.859000Z</updated>
  <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/index.atom" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/" type="text/html" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Larson</name>
      <email>eric@ionrock.org</email>
      <uri>http://ionrock.org/blog/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>urn:uuid:292079c6-1623-11dc-809e-0017f2ddcdba</id>
    <updated>2007-06-08T19:48:38Z</updated>
    <published>2007-06-08T19:48:38Z</published>
    <title>Technology for the Sake of Humans</title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">One interesting thing about technology is that it really is pointless outside of a user. Of course there are systems that function without human intervention, but at the end of day, systems function to help users. This is not a revelation or anything insanely profound, but just a little concept that it is good to bring to the forefront every once in a while. You know, to keep it real. </div>
    </content>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/06/08/Technology_for_the_Sake_of_Humans.atom" rel="self" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/06/08/Technology_for_the_Sake_of_Humans.atom" rel="edit" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/06/08/Technology_for_the_Sake_of_Humans/" rel="alternate" title="alternate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://blog.sonicradar.com/2007/04/16/premature-optimization/</id>
    <category term="General" scheme="http://blog.sonicradar.com"/>
    <category term="mash-up" scheme="http://blog.sonicradar.com"/>
    <category term="Atom" scheme="http://blog.sonicradar.com"/>
    <title>Premature Optimization</title>
    <published>2007-04-16T16:29:16Z</published>
    <updated>2007-04-16T16:30:19Z</updated>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The web has been
            optimized prematurely. People have thought about web applications in terms of PHP and
            the result is the web as we have it today. It is due for a rewrite and many folks would
            argue that Web 2.0 is just that, a rewrite of the web. In a way this is true [...]</div>
    </summary>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>The web has been optimized prematurely.
            People have thought about web applications in terms of PHP and the result is the web as
            we have it today. It is due for a rewrite and many folks would argue that Web 2.0 is
            just that, a rewrite of the web. In a way this is true but I would argue that Web 2.0
            (we all love buzzwords right?) is really more of a <a href="http://docs.python.org/lib/module-unittest.html">unittest</a>
            getting things ready for the actual code that will be written.</p>
        <p>When I first became interested in computers, it was through <a href="http://www.linux.org/">Linux</a>. The command line was an
            interesting application of sorts because there was elegance hidden behind simplicity. It
            has been said that Google has taken this simplicity and essentially creating find + grep
            for the web. The best thing about the command line was that it was an application that
            other applications could use. It is this intrinsic design pattern in Unix that made it
            such a powerful platform that emphasized reuse and never required optimizations before
            necessary.</p>
        <p>The web on the other hand has made a very
            specific optimization to hold all the data on a central server to make sure there is no
            redundancy. Bandwidth has been primarily the responsibility of the server because the
            data has been placed there. The browser is the input device of choice, which arguably
            presents security concerns, so no DELETEs or PUTs. Scaling pushed its way to the
            forefront of web development prematurely and the resulting web applications have been
            crippled by their own requirements, almost none of which were actually
            required.</p>
        <p>Before I go on, I should mention this is
            not a rant against PHP or web developers. There are millions of applications on the web
            that are amazing and effective. What I suggest is simply refactoring to take advantage
            of new features and get rid of cruft that is not necessary anymore. With that
            said…</p>
        <p>The solution to this is to create
            a shell for the web. We need stdout and stdin and everything should be a file.
            Fortunately we already have the workings of it with Atom Publishing Protocol. APP
            essentially gives life to a file, which is the basis of *nix where everything is a file.
            APP makes no effort to stop data redundancy or implement a push architecture. APP
            assumes the user’s client is doing a good job and tries to respect the
            information it receives. In a nutshell, APP gives the web a file.</p>
        <p>Within the scope of SonicRadar, this is crucial. If everything is a
            file then musicians can mount their files in /home/MyBand and my application read from
            /home/MyBand/shows to see when they are playing. Even though a network may or may not be
            involved, I never know and I don’t care to know. If I want to see the
            shows of different bands playing in my town, it is simply a matter of getting each file
            and using grep. The idea here is that instead of every web application reimplementing
            things like ls and cd, we create an environment for people to reuse the
            basics.</p>
        <p>This idea is not new of course. It is simply
            within reach. SonicRadar will allow everyone to have a true
            ‘~’ on the web instead of logging into the VPN just to
            access a silly mapped ‘Z:’ drive.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Larson</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:google.com,2005:reader/feed/http://blog.sonicradar.com/feed/atom/</id>
      <title>blog.sonicradar.com</title>
    </source>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/04/16/Premature_Optimization.atom" rel="self" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/04/16/Premature_Optimization.atom" rel="edit" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/04/16/Premature_Optimization/" rel="alternate" title="permalink"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://blog.sonicradar.com/2007/04/11/the-art-of-xforms/</id>
    <category term="mash-up" scheme="http://blog.sonicradar.com"/>
    <category term="Atom" scheme="http://blog.sonicradar.com"/>
    <category term="xforms" scheme="http://blog.sonicradar.com"/>
    <title>The Art of XForms</title>
    <published>2007-04-11T14:59:18Z</published>
    <updated>2007-04-11T14:59:18Z</updated>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I have high hopes
            for XForms. As someone who is familiar with user interface design and interaction
            design, I can honestly say that as a developer the cost/reward ratio is skewed. There is
            a vast amount of work that is required to add features that are arguably inconsequential
            to better usability. XForms has the ability [...]</div>
    </summary>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>I have high hopes for XForms. As someone who is familiar
            with user interface design and interaction design, I can honestly say that as a
            developer the cost/reward ratio is skewed. There is a vast amount of work that is
            required to add features that are arguably inconsequential to better usability. XForms
            has the ability to reduce the amount work by doing the same type of rendering that the
            browser provides for HTML. This is huge.</p>
        <p>The impact
            of this means that an interface can be created for a service almost as easily as HTML
            can be created. I remember when I first learned HTML and saw how simple it was to create
            a page. Nowadays you see wiki markup and a multitude of text formats that allow easy
            translation from text to markup. It reflects the practiced boundary between style and
            content, which has been critical in making the web what it is today. When you think of
            things like Google Pages or any wiki, you see a situation where the user is asked to
            provide content which gets styled. The result is that adding content has become easy
            enough that we have Wikipedia and millions of bloggers.</p>
        <p>The next step in this evolution is building forms to get user input and
            send it to some service. PayPal has done this to some extent but they have had a pretty
            simple model where a button gets the user 80% of what they need and usually is enough.
            In a more complex service it would be nice to give someone an example piece of XML and
            then create forms (via XForms) that submits the XML to the service. Before going on, you
            should read that sentence again because there is a subtle point to
            see…</p>
        <p>The key phrase there is
            “<strong>give someone an
            example</strong>.” Instead of describing RELAX NG syntax to
            a service, if someone provides a basic template for what the input should look like, a
            person could copy and paste it into an XForms editor. The XForms editor creates a quick
            sample template of the forms and you start adding requirements according to your own
            needs. Better yet, someone can just give you the forms and be done with
            it!</p>
        <p>The result is that the creativity you see on the
            web can be applied to interfaces without having to understand event models or callbacks.
            Sure, there will probably be something of a geocities phase where text areas have
            animated people walking around the cursor. But, soon after you will see people creating
            innovative ways to gather data from users. More importantly, users will be able to
            create their own custom world to use with their favorite services. It will be like the
            world magically learned Lisp and the web browser became Emacs… You know
            what I mean… Right? <img src="http://blog.sonicradar.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)"/></p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Larson</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:google.com,2005:reader/feed/http://blog.sonicradar.com/feed/atom/</id>
      <title>blog.sonicradar.com</title>
    </source>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/04/11/The_Art_of_XForms.atom" rel="self" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/04/11/The_Art_of_XForms.atom" rel="edit" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/04/11/The_Art_of_XForms/" rel="alternate" title="permalink"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://blog.sonicradar.com/2007/04/09/go-figure/</id>
    <category term="General" scheme="http://blog.sonicradar.com"/>
    <title>Go figure</title>
    <published>2007-04-09T21:06:51Z</published>
    <updated>2007-04-10T12:38:31Z</updated>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today I went to my
            local HMV to browse their CDs. I don’t know if you are like me but I often
            tell myself “you should note this album down and look up for it next time
            you’ll get there”. Now if you’re anything like
            me you never do such thing. So it’s usually when [...]</div>
    </summary>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Today I went to my local <a href="http://www.hmv.co.uk">HMV</a> to browse their CDs. I
            don’t know if you are like me but I often tell myself “you
            should note this album down and look up for it next time you’ll get
            there”. Now if you’re anything like me you never do such
            thing. So it’s usually when I end up at the store that I realize I wanted
            to search for an artist’s album and fail to remember who and what. Anyway
            today I was browsing their catalog without much idea of what I wanted except it had to
            be someone I had never heard. I do so to force myself into listening to different
            things. I ended up piling up around height CDs.</p>
        <p>Now
            considering the crazy prices HMV applies to some indie or rather unknown bands I wanted
            to have an idea of what I would buy. I therefore headed towards their (unique) working
            station where you search for an artist, album or song. If you’re lucky you
            can listen to it. Hint, I said “If you’re
            lucky”. Truth is most albums they actually upload there come from famous
            bands and artists (well that’s far fetched a word in many cases but
            that’s beside the point). So out of my height albums only one was
            available to be listened to. I wasn’t moving forward, was
            I?</p>
        <p>Slightly pissed off, I went to ask one of the HMV
            vendor what the hell was going on. He explained that the machine they used to convert
            the songs to MP3 was broken and they didn’t know when they’d
            get a new one. I blinked and I said “what’s the point for me
            to come down here? I should just download the files from the Internet
            instead.”. He nodded and looked sorry.</p>
        <p>So here we are, huge chains like HMV, which are blaming the piracy and
            those who don’t pay a penny, cannot even afford a descent streaming
            system, allowing people to gage an album before spending their cash on
            it.</p>
        <p>I mean when an album costs £15 (around $30) you
            tend to ensure you will like it as a whole. If I can’t do that at the
            shop, I will do it online and then, what stops me from actually getting the file for
            free anyway? </p>
        <p>For free? Well yes because when I went
            to the <a href="http://www.hmvdigital.com">HMV Digital</a>
            website I got the following message:</p>
        <blockquote>
          <p>This site relies on ActiveX technology to
            download music to your machine; at this time you need Internet Explorer version 6 or
            greater running on Windows XP or Windows 2000 to purchase and download
            music.</p>
          <p>We hope to add Firefox support soon. In the
            mean time, why not subscribe to our RSS feeds to keep up to date with the latest
            releases.</p>
        </blockquote>
        <p>Now that means
            that from Linux I can’t get to their service. Well too bad for them. (I
            will pass on the blatant attempt to make me believe that they will either rewrite their
            entire application without ActiveX or find a way to support ActiveX from within Firefox
            natively).</p>
        <p>Where does that leave us? Well as the
            title says “Go figure.”.</p>
        <p>Now I did buy three CDs anyway: Pearl Jam - Ten, Little Barrie - We are
            little barrie, James Harries - Days Like These. I have not been disappointed so
            far.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Sylvain Hellegouarch</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:google.com,2005:reader/feed/http://blog.sonicradar.com/feed/atom/</id>
      <title>blog.sonicradar.com</title>
    </source>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/04/09/Go_figure.atom" rel="self" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/04/09/Go_figure.atom" rel="edit" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/04/09/Go_figure/" rel="alternate" title="permalink"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://blog.sonicradar.com/2007/04/07/randomsounds-the-gateway-center-salt-lake-city-ut-bellevue-christian-concert-choir/</id>
    <category term="random.sounds" scheme="http://blog.sonicradar.com"/>
    <title>Random.Sounds: The Gateway Center, Salt Lake City, UT |
            Bellevue Christian Concert Choir</title>
    <published>2007-04-08T04:03:00Z</published>
    <updated>2007-04-08T04:25:09Z</updated>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  I
            was out for a walk earlier this afternoon and came across this incredible performance by
            what I believe is the Bellevue Christian Concert Choir (I spoke with some of the
            students afterwords (pictured below) and they mentioned they were from Bellevue
            Christian School.) Video: Bellevue Christian Concert Choir @ The Gateway Center, Salt
            Lake City, [...]</div>
    </summary>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>I was out for a walk earlier this afternoon and came across this
            incredible performance by what I believe is the <a href="http://www.bellevuechristian.org/content-en/programs/performing_arts.php">Bellevue
            Christian Concert Choir</a> (I spoke with some of the students afterwords
            (pictured below) and they mentioned they were from <a href="http://www.bellevuechristian.org/">Bellevue Christian
            School</a>.)</p>
        <p>
               <embed width="412" src="http://images.soapbox.msn.com/flash/soapbox1_1.swf"
                      flashvars="c=v&amp;amp;v=dcaf0a80-f385-4375-92cf-04a4e03b410f"
                      allowScriptAccess="never"
                      height="362"/>
               <br/><a href="http://soapbox.msn.com/video.aspx?vid=dcaf0a80-f385-4375-92cf-04a4e03b410f" title="Bellevue Christian Concert Choir @ The Gateway Center, Salt Lake City, UT">Video:
            Bellevue Christian Concert Choir @ The Gateway Center, Salt Lake City,
            UT</a><p>Beyond the performance, and the acoustics of the
            room, what I found most amazing about this experience was to see how many students had
            digital cameras with them, and how many of those cameras were
            video-enabled.</p><p><a href="http://blog.sonicradar.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/04/windowslivewriterrandomsoundsthegatewaycentersaltlakecity-12f38dsc0053362.jpg"><img src="http://blog.sonicradar.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/04/windowslivewriterrandomsoundsthegatewaycentersaltlakecity-12f38dsc00533-thumb42.jpg" style="border-right:0px;border-top:0px;border-left:0px;border-bottom:0px" border="0" width="447" height="350"/></a></p><p>We’re entering a whole new world, my friends, where
            traditional media can no longer keep up with what’s going on around the
            world at the same pace that 100 million info-hungry
            ‘tweeners are as quickly, easily, and affordably equipped as
            they both are and can be to report the news as it’s happening
            to anyone with access to the internet.  Add to this an equivalent number of
            30, 40, and 50 somethings, an increasingly technologically
            savvy group of retired folk, and, of course, the popularity of sites such
            as <a href="http://www.youtube.com/">YouTube</a> and I think
            we can easily assume that within 10 years time the newscasts as we know them will be no
            longer.</p><p>Just my opinion, of course, and I have every
            reason to believe that these same media agencies will find ways to adapt. 
            </p><p>But they’d better adapt quickly.
            <img src="http://blog.sonicradar.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";-)"/></p></p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>M. David Peterson</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:google.com,2005:reader/feed/http://blog.sonicradar.com/feed/atom/</id>
      <title>blog.sonicradar.com</title>
    </source>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/04/08/Random_Sounds__The_Gateway_Center__Salt_Lake_City__UT____Bellevue_Christian_Concert_Choir.atom" rel="self" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/04/08/Random_Sounds__The_Gateway_Center__Salt_Lake_City__UT____Bellevue_Christian_Concert_Choir.atom" rel="edit" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/04/08/Random_Sounds__The_Gateway_Center__Salt_Lake_City__UT____Bellevue_Christian_Concert_Choir/" rel="alternate" title="permalink"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://blog.sonicradar.com/2007/04/04/offline-applications/</id>
    <category term="General" scheme="http://blog.sonicradar.com"/>
    <category term="mash-up" scheme="http://blog.sonicradar.com"/>
    <category term="Atom" scheme="http://blog.sonicradar.com"/>
    <title>Offline Applications</title>
    <published>2007-04-04T15:58:00Z</published>
    <updated>2007-04-04T15:58:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">There has been a
            good deal of discussion recently regarding offline web applications. The impetus for
            this conversation stem from Joyent’s Slingshot. Dave’s
            response was that you don’t need offline web applications and in a way I
            agree. Joyent’s response cleared up a good deal of confusion and put the
            concept in context. The short [...]</div>
    </summary>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>There has been a good deal of discussion
            recently regarding offline web applications. The impetus for this conversation stem from
            <a href="http://joyeur.com">Joyent’s</a><a href="http://joyeur.com/2007/03/22/joyent-slingshot">Slingshot</a>.
            Dave’s response was that <a href="http://www.37signals.com/svn/posts/347-youre-not-on-a-fucking-plane-and-if-you-are-it-doesnt-matter">you
            don’t need offline web applications</a> and in a way I
            agree. Joyent’s <a href="http://joyeur.com/2007/04/02/slingshot-apologia-we-didnt-design-slingshot-for-planes">response</a>
            cleared up a good deal of confusion and put the concept in context. The short and skinny
            is that the offline web is partly about working on planes, but primarily is about one
            means of interfacing with the user.</p>
        <p>I should be
            specific. If you have every programmed a user interface for Windows.Forms with
            IronPython you quickly realize that Windows.Forms was not meant to typed by humans. The
            classes are all designed to be created via Visual Studio. There is nothing wrong with it
            of course and I am sure others would disagree with me. The issue is that designing a
            user interface is complicated. Think about writing RTF, PostScript, XSL-FO, etc. and you
            immediately see that making a visual image of something via a text based language is not
            very easy.</p>
        <p>The web browser helps a bit with this and
            provides a valuable constraint. You don’t get tons of drag and drop
            controls with datagrid views, but users don’t expect them. You
            don’t have millions of event handlers (well you could, but you really
            don’t need them) because the web is stateless. Separating design from
            content is almost a given and there is an actual divide between the
            “View” (the rendered HTML) and the
            “Controller” (whatever the server is doing). The real
            benefit of “offline” web applications is that you get to
            program for the web without the web and that is appealing.</p>
        <p>This is not a silver bullet of course. On the usability front it
            potentially makes user interfaces inconsistent. Interesting usability concepts could
            also be dropped on the floor simply be implementations are too difficult. Another issue
            is that the platform is regulated by browser makers, which could potentially prevent UI
            innovation. In a way both of these concerns are valid, but overall I think it really
            doesn’t matter. Users have learned to use the web and appreciate the
            benefits they get web applications such that browser based offline applications that
            help to interact with online services will provide more than enough usefulness to make
            almost any user interface worth learning. A user interface is nothing without a user, so
            making applications that have users is a must before trying to make life better for the
            users.</p>
        <p>The concept of interaction with online
            services is the critical aspect in this whole equation. The WS-* stack has proven itself
            to somewhat ill suited for generic services, whereas the browser has become an amazing
            platform for viewing and interacting with information. I believe the Atom Publishing
            Protocol answers this need by providing a thin, atomic wrapper around the traditional
            web based interface where clients can be much more affective. With this simple RESTful
            protocol, offline client applications can easily provide customized interfaces to
            services while happily staying within the confines of the web browser.</p>
        <p>Within the context of SonicRadar, this means creating one system that
            can be used online or offline through the browser. It means that individuality is no
            long adding another class to an application on a server. Instead it means providing a
            new service or creating a new interface to a service. In a way this small distinction is
            of little consequence to users, but as people more and more accustomed to having their
            data available online all the times it becomes increasingly important to have control
            over that data.</p>
        <p>By the way, control is
            <strong>not</strong> storage of the data. Control is how you
            interact with data. As a problem solver, I can invert the problem to see another angle
            in how to solve it. As a web user I am provided a proprietary portal to canned
            information. What I want is to have many ways to see information. Aggregators provide
            this very functionality and considering the success of RSS/Atom feeds, I think applying
            this principle to the entire web makes sense. Offline web applications make this
            possible because the technology used to provide the services can be used on the client
            as is and there no longer is a constant battle between developers and the
            system’s of their users.</p>
        <p>Java, C#,
            Python, Ruby, PHP, etc. all allow programmers to write code without worrying about the
            operating system. This was not the goal. The goal was to allow programmers to write code
            without worry about the
            <strong>user’s</strong> operating system. The
            client side web continues this tradition and I am on board.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Larson</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:google.com,2005:reader/feed/http://blog.sonicradar.com/feed/atom/</id>
      <title>blog.sonicradar.com</title>
    </source>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/04/04/Offline_Applications.atom" rel="self" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/04/04/Offline_Applications.atom" rel="edit" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/04/04/Offline_Applications/" rel="alternate" title="permalink"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://blog.sonicradar.com/2007/03/29/open-source-on-the-web/</id>
    <category term="General" scheme="http://blog.sonicradar.com"/>
    <category term="mash-up" scheme="http://blog.sonicradar.com"/>
    <category term="social network" scheme="http://blog.sonicradar.com"/>
    <title>Open Source on the Web</title>
    <published>2007-03-29T14:51:08Z</published>
    <updated>2007-03-29T14:51:08Z</updated>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I read this article
            from Dare regarding Open Source being “dead” because social
            software requires some central element. In a way I agree with him. Social software is
            essentially just a web application that has many users. It is not the software itself
            that makes it helpful, it is the marriage of technology and a [...]</div>
    </summary>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>I read <a href="http://www.25hoursaday.com/weblog/PermaLink.aspx?guid=69141977-7514-443d-800b-1f95c1ff8dbe">this</a>
            article from Dare regarding Open Source being “dead” because
            social software requires some central element. In a way I agree with him. Social
            software is essentially just a web application that has many users. It is not the
            software itself that makes it helpful, it is the marriage of technology and a bountiful
            user base that gives it value.</p>
        <p>The assumption is the
            browser will always be the interface for social software. I do not think the browser is
            going away. But I do think that other types of clients will become more important as
            social software continues to create more than social situations. My favorite example of
            this is MySpace and the abuse of the profile section. A custom MySpace profile manager
            would be a nice little application to have for creating slick themes. It would be nice
            as well to aggregate parts of MySpace to other sites (this would be especially helpful
            to musicians I think). At this point MySpace breaks down because the entire profile
            customization system is essentially just a hack. MySpace could benefit by producing a
            real API for customization that the clients can implement.</p>
        <p>This really is just the traditional “Web
            3.0″ kind of talk. The idea of moving beyond mash-ups into real deal
            aggregation of disparate content for a cohesive message. I am doubting MySpace will lead
            the charge into this kind of space, but you never know. I do think the Open Source
            community will (and has) lead this movement. Sure they will not be writing the great web
            service that folks are using, but they will be writing the clients and specs that users
            enjoy.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Larson</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:google.com,2005:reader/feed/http://blog.sonicradar.com/feed/atom/</id>
      <title>blog.sonicradar.com</title>
    </source>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/03/29/Open_Source_on_the_Web.atom" rel="self" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/03/29/Open_Source_on_the_Web.atom" rel="edit" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/03/29/Open_Source_on_the_Web/" rel="alternate" title="permalink"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://blog.sonicradar.com/2007/03/27/on-punk/</id>
    <category term="General" scheme="http://blog.sonicradar.com"/>
    <title>On Punk</title>
    <published>2007-03-27T22:21:19Z</published>
    <updated>2007-03-27T22:22:14Z</updated>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">My musical
            background stems primarily from punk. As I have gotten older and arguably less
            ‘punk’, I have made an effort to understand what the essence
            of punk truly is. To me, punk encompasses two primary concepts. Community To be
            “punk” is to be a part of a community. The idea is that
            without some audience for [...]</div>
    </summary>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>My musical background stems primarily from punk. As I have gotten
            older and arguably less ‘punk’, I have made an effort to
            understand what the essence of punk truly is. To me, punk encompasses two primary
            concepts.</p>
        <p>
          <strong>Community</strong>
        </p>
        <p>To be “punk” is to be a part of a
            community. The idea is that without some audience for actions, there is no way to
            recognize whether you are acting “punk” or not. Beyond the
            obviousness of an audience, a punk mentality involves a respect for other persons. I say
            “persons” because the respect is not necessarily for a group
            of people. Instead, it is important to have respect for each and every
            person’s individuality.</p>
        <p>Before going on
            I should mention that the “punk” I grew up on was the breed
            from DC. Minor Threat and Dischord helped define my concept of punk, which was then
            confirmed as I moved through other punk genres. In other words, I never wore a leather
            jacket, squatted, did heroin, shaved my head/had a mohawk or did any of the other
            potentially traditionally punk activities.</p>
        <p>
          <strong>Questions</strong>
        </p>
        <p>In order to be punk you really need to be wary of belief. I am not
            saying you shouldn’t believe in something, but rather that a person who is
            punk believes in something because they have asked questions and found answers that
            drove them to believe something. This is also the root of “questioning
            authority” or “questioning societal norms” or
            any other more obvious punk mantra.</p>
        <p>To sum it up,
            being punk is respecting others and making an effort to understand.</p>
        <p>Now, I mention this here because up until this point I have discussed
            the “business” side of music and it is important that folks
            do not misinterpret who I am. My music is my art and it is how I can express myself and
            provide something other people can relate to and enjoy. I have found in my questioning
            of the music industry, that the numerical majority of people involved are honest and
            caring folks that share in my passions. I know many people see the music industry as a
            terrible place where musicians lose their souls and sacrifice their integrity for a
            fleeting few moments of fame while record companies make big bucks at the expense of
            real of people. While this happens, the majority of people who work in the music
            industry (this includes the bookers, indie labels, publicists, promoters, musicians,
            designers, etc.) barely scrape by out of their love of music.</p>
        <p>While it may not appear very ‘punk’ to try
            and help improve the music industry as a whole, it is punk to try. I think every person
            who goes on a tour, puts out a record or simply goes to see a band live is worth the
            time if their passion for music can be supported. So, if you think I am always talking
            like a capitalistic jerk who cares nothing for artistic expression, please have a bit of
            perspective. I want friends of mine who tour and run labels to have insurance. I want
            local bands in town to not need to go to the pharmaceutical testing labs every month to
            pay for recordings. I want clubs to be able to pay touring bands enough for gas *and*
            food. In other words, no one is saying that folks need huge houses, tons of cars and
            plastic surgery, simply a reasonable wage for a ton of hard work.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Larson</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:google.com,2005:reader/feed/http://blog.sonicradar.com/feed/atom/</id>
      <title>blog.sonicradar.com</title>
    </source>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/03/27/On_Punk.atom" rel="self" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/03/27/On_Punk.atom" rel="edit" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/03/27/On_Punk/" rel="alternate" title="permalink"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://blog.sonicradar.com/2007/03/27/welcome-to-ffado/</id>
    <category term="General" scheme="http://blog.sonicradar.com"/>
    <title>Welcome to FFADO</title>
    <published>2007-03-27T20:43:55Z</published>
    <updated>2007-03-27T20:44:46Z</updated>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">FreeBoB is now
            named FFADO which stands for Free Firewire Audio Drivers. FreeBoB is a project that aims
            at providing support for audio devices using FireWire and espacially the BeBoB firmware.
            I cannot praise enough for that project considering those guys allowed me to use my
            M-Audio FireWire Solo on my beloved Linux distribution. They seem [...]</div>
    </summary>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p><a href="http://freebob.sourceforge.net">FreeBoB</a> is now named
            <strong>FFADO</strong> which stands for
            <em>Free Firewire Audio Drivers</em>. FreeBoB is a project
            that aims at providing support for audio devices using FireWire and espacially the
            <a href="http://freebob.sourceforge.net/index.php/BeBoB">BeBoB</a>
            firmware. I cannot praise enough for that project considering those guys allowed me to
            use my <a href="http://www.m-audio.com/products/en_us/FireWireSolo-main.html">M-Audio
            FireWire Solo</a> on my beloved <a href="http://www.mepis.org/">Linux
            distribution</a>.</p>
        <p>They seem to be
            changing their name because they plan on supporting any audio device using FireWire.
            This is a huge news for the entire community and we must welcome their
            decision.</p>
        <p>I would like to say that the support of
            high end audio devices under Linux is usually poor from the vendors themselves and they
            should be ashamed since the platform is fantastic for performing audio and music
            work.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Sylvain Hellegouarch</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:google.com,2005:reader/feed/http://blog.sonicradar.com/feed/atom/</id>
      <title>blog.sonicradar.com</title>
    </source>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/03/27/Welcome_to_FFADO.atom" rel="self" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/03/27/Welcome_to_FFADO.atom" rel="edit" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/03/27/Welcome_to_FFADO/" rel="alternate" title="permalink"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://blog.sonicradar.com/2007/03/22/working-musicians/</id>
    <category term="General" scheme="http://blog.sonicradar.com"/>
    <title>Working Musicians</title>
    <published>2007-03-22T15:38:20Z</published>
    <updated>2007-03-22T15:38:20Z</updated>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I read an article
            on TechCrunch regarding how it was good that CD sales were down. There is an idea major
            labels make huge margins and the lowered CD sales is the market correcting that. The
            more I think about these topics the more I wish there was more research on the subject
            because there [...]</div>
    </summary>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>I read an article on <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2007/03/21/good-news-cd-music-sales-down-20-from-2006/">TechCrunch</a>
            regarding how it was good that CD sales were down. There is an idea major labels make
            huge margins and the lowered CD sales is the market correcting that. The more I think
            about these topics the more I wish there was more research on the subject because there
            is no way to speak authoritatively without really knowing what the books look like.
            Specifically, the article mentions it will be good when labels realize they cannot make
            huge profits. Part of me thinks this is good, but overall I wonder then who will make
            money because if artists are not making it when there is an abundance of funds, I am
            doubting anything will improve when there is less money to go around.</p>
        <p>One theme I see in articles like this is the lack of understanding
            regarding the amount of work that goes into making a band successful. From the actual
            music to the company hired to create a slick MySpace theme, there are tons of people
            involved and most of the time the money must be paid up front without any guarantees on
            how the record will do. It is similar to venture capital firms in that if the company
            does not do well, they are simply out of luck. I wonder if there are other industries
            that have been built off of a rather fickle marketplace and still have relatively
            traditional profit margins.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Larson</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:google.com,2005:reader/feed/http://blog.sonicradar.com/feed/atom/</id>
      <title>blog.sonicradar.com</title>
    </source>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/03/22/Working_Musicians.atom" rel="self" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/03/22/Working_Musicians.atom" rel="edit" title="atom"/>
    <link href="http://sonicradar.com/blog/2007/03/22/Working_Musicians/" rel="alternate" title="permalink"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
